<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://bvieuble.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://bvieuble.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-02-07T12:39:46+00:00</updated><id>https://bvieuble.me/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Academic visit in China (1/3)</title><link href="https://bvieuble.me/blog/2025/chinavisit1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Academic visit in China (1/3)"/><published>2025-01-10T00:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-10T00:01:00+00:00</updated><id>https://bvieuble.me/blog/2025/chinavisit1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://bvieuble.me/blog/2025/chinavisit1/"><![CDATA[<style>body{text-align:justify}</style> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blog/passport-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blog/passport-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blog/passport-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/blog/passport.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> <h2 id="invited-by-peers-in-china-you-are-at-the-good-place">Invited by peers in China? You are at the good place!</h2> <p>You are a senior or young researcher and have been invited by a peer to give a talk at a Chinese institute or university, to give a class, to attend a conference or a workshop? You wish to accept but wonder if you need to apply for a visa? And if so, what documents do you need for the application? How to organize your trip? What you should know before going? How will you sustain yourself when you’re there? Say no more, you are at the right place!</p> <p>First things first, if you are dealing with a renowned Chinese academic institute, you can sit back and relax, you are in good hands! They know their business, you are not the first foreigner they invite and you won’t be the last. Your Chinese peers will take it to heart to provide you with the best and smoothest experience. In all fairness, you’ll likely be provided with more accurate instructions and information than this simple blog post. Yet, as I was once in your exact situation, I might still be able to provide you with some good tips.</p> <p>This little guide is organized into three parts. In the first part, which you are reading right now, we will cover your right of entry into mainland Chinese territory. This includes your eligibility for visa exemption and, if not eligible, the procedure to apply for a visa for the purpose of an academic visit.</p> <h2 id="visa-or-not-visa">Visa or not visa?</h2> <p>Ultimately, if you read this post, you are likely NOT to hold a Chinese passport or a Chinese residence permit. Hence, you need to carefully check the rules that apply to you to enter mainland Chinese territory. Regulations in the matter have highly fluctuated these last few years, most often in the direction of leveraging or simplifying the requirements. Hence, at the time you read this post, certain information I present might be incomplete or wrong. I therefore strongly recommend checking the regulations presented on the official websites of your government or the websites of the Chinese embassies, consulates, or visa application centers in your country.</p> <h3 id="visa-exemption">Visa exemption</h3> <p>As of today, if you hold a passport from a country in the European Union, East Asia, Oceania, and more, the chance is you can be exempt from holding a visa for academic exchange for a duration of less than 30 days. This would give you far enough time to attend most workshops, conferences, or seminars. The most reliable way to know if you are eligible for such an exemption is to check the travel information provided by your government or the Chinese embassies in your home country. You can also check the <a href="https://travelchina.guide/visa/free">Travel China</a> website which lists the visa-exempt countries, or find some official information on the <a href="https://www.mfa.gov.cn/wjbzwfwpt/kzx/tzgg/202411/t20241130_11535783.html">Chinese government</a> website.</p> <blockquote class="block-tip"> <h5 id="-valid-purposes-of-visit-for-visa-exemption">✅ Valid purposes of visit for visa exemption</h5> <p>The exemptions generally cover entries on mainland Chinese territory for the purpose of business, tourism, family or friends visits, exchange, and transit. Short academic visits fall within the “exchange” classification.</p> </blockquote> <p>Be careful, being exempt from holding a visa does not mean you can arrive at the border unprepared. You need to be ready to provide to the border agent some proof of the purpose of your visit if asked. In the case of a short academic visit, it falls down to the following documents:</p> <ul> <li>A <strong>valid passport</strong> (I mean…).</li> <li>An <strong>invitation letter</strong> from your academic host in China. The letter should be addressed to you and should provide basic information, such as a short description of the activities you will engage in, the dates of your visit to the host institution, the host’s contact information, etc.</li> <li><strong>Airplane tickets</strong>, especially the flight out of China.</li> <li>Reservations of <strong>accommodation</strong>. If you are staying in a hotel, just be ready to provide the hotel reservations. If you are not staying in a hotel, things are a bit more complicated, and the official recommendations I could find are vague. If your academic host provides you with other form of accommodation, I think the host should mention it on the invitation letter or provide you with another document mentioning it. If you stay at a relative or friend’s place, ask them for a letter indicating the address and the stay dates. In addition, ask them to provide you with a scan of their Chinese ID. Beware that if you are not staying in a hotel, you will have to register at the police station within 24 hours; more is said about this in section <a href="https://bvieuble.me/blog/2025/chinavisit3/#hotel">Hotel</a>.</li> </ul> <blockquote class="block-warning"> <h5 id="️-the-phd-student-case">⚠️ The PhD student case</h5> <p>Beware that a visa exemption does not cover entrance to mainland Chinese territory for the purpose of work, journalism, and <strong>STUDY</strong>. In particular, in China, a PhD student is fully considered a “student”. Hence, if you are a PhD student, it should be clarified with your host institution or organism in China if your visit falls within the “study” or “exchange” classification. With the first, you are provided with an admission notice or letter that you should use to apply for a study visa. With the second, you should be provided with an invitation letter and, depending on your nationality, can be exempt from holding a visa.</p> </blockquote> <h3 id="if-you-need-a-visa">If you need a visa</h3> <p>There are different kinds of visas you can apply for to enter mainland Chinese territory, and all have different requirements. The type of visa you need depends on the purpose and length of your visit. If you are coming to China for a short academic trip (e.g., invited to give a talk at a seminar, visiting a scholar for collaboration, attending conferences or workshops, etc.), you likely need an F visa. You can find more detailed information about F visa on <a href="https://www.travelchinaguide.com/embassy/visa/f-visa.htm">Travel China Guide</a> for instance. In addition, a step-by-step visa application guide can be found on <a href="https://travelchina.guide/visa/application">Travel China</a>.</p> <p>In short, you should be asked to provide the following documents to apply for an F visa:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Passport</strong> with two blank visa pages, plus a photocopy of the passport’s bio page.</li> <li>A <strong>Visa Application Form</strong> which has to be filled out online on the <a href="https://bio.visaforchina.cn/">Chinese visa Application Center</a> website and which should be printed and signed. Note that you must pick the country/city where you wish to apply for the visa at this step.</li> <li>Passport-sized <strong>photo</strong> in color and with a white background.</li> <li>An <strong>official invitation letter</strong> from your host. A scanned and printed version of the letter is generally acceptable. Sometimes, the invitation mentions the city where you must apply for the visa. For this reason, let your host know early on which city you would like to submit your application.</li> <li>A proof of legal residence if you are applying in a country other than your home country (e.g., a visa or residence permit).</li> </ul> <p>Once you have filled and validated the application on the <a href="https://bio.visaforchina.cn/">Chinese visa Application Center</a> website, you must bring all the required documents to the visa application center of the city of your choice. From my understanding, appointments are no longer required in many visa centers, and you can visit the center during working hours to submit the application at the time of your convenience. You will also have to pay the visa fee at the center while applying.</p> <p>Again, this is a very important business and you don’t want to mess it up, so don’t take my words for granted and check carefully the requirements that apply to you on the <a href="https://bio.visaforchina.cn/">Chinese visa Application Center</a> website. After you have entered your country and city of application on the aforementioned website, you can go to the <em>Visa Category</em> link to learn more about the requirements and documents you need to prepare.</p> <blockquote class="block-warning"> <h5 id="️-using-a-visa-agency">⚠️ Using a visa agency</h5> <p>If you live far away from your nearest visa center, you might be tempted to use a third-party visa agency. With their services, you can apply for visas from the comfort of your home without having to travel to the visa centers or embassies yourself. HOWEVER, in the case of Chinese visa application, beware that you may or may not be required to come to the visa center in person to have your fingerprints taken! You should consider contacting the visa agency before booking their services to verify if you can avoid the trip to the center.</p> </blockquote> <h2 id="list-of-useful-material">List of useful material</h2> <ul> <li>Visa exemption: <a href="https://travelchina.guide/visa/free">Travel China</a>, <a href="https://www.mfa.gov.cn/wjbzwfwpt/kzx/tzgg/202411/t20241130_11535783.html">Chinese government</a></li> <li>F visa application: <a href="https://www.travelchinaguide.com/embassy/visa/f-visa.htm">Travel China Guide</a></li> <li>Tuto for visa application: <a href="https://travelchina.guide/visa/application">Travel China</a></li> <li>Applying for a visa online: <a href="https://bio.visaforchina.cn">Chinese Visa Application Center</a></li> </ul> <h2 id="continue-the-guide">Continue the Guide</h2> <ul> <li>Continue to Part 2 (internet, payments, and other essentials): <a href="https://bvieuble.me/blog/2025/chinavisit2">Academic visit in China (2/3)</a></li> <li>Continue to Part 3 (once arrived): <a href="https://bvieuble.me/blog/2025/chinavisit3">Academic visit in China (3/3)</a></li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="chinalife"/><category term="china"/><category term="travel"/><category term="visit"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everything you need to know about preparing your short academic visit in China. Part 1/3 - Introduction and visa.]]></summary></entry></feed>